{
    "id": "1fcc95f30e1346a0bee0dc7af1eb7fd7",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He plans to start his own business in ……………….. years.",
            "description": "We can say ‘a few years’ or ‘a couple of’ years.",
            "answers": [
                "few",
                "a few",
                "a couple"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "39f92b531db64ea582e9d9bd34cde3a4"
        },
        {
            "question": "Yesterday, I saw the movie that my friends ………………… the week before.",
            "description": "We use the past perfect for the earlier of two past actions.",
            "answers": [
                "saw",
                "have seen",
                "had seen"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "616969e72e004e9183d8c9bc88248ec4"
        },
        {
            "question": "She embarked …………. a career in law graduating from a prestigious law school.",
            "description": "The correct expression is ‘embark on’.",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "at",
                "in",
                "to"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "916ee74d9252474b8671fc038f369ec8"
        },
        {
            "question": "We must guard ourselves …………… all possible infections.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "of",
                "against",
                "with"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "950901f5091c4639a6b91157bbce6a7d"
        },
        {
            "question": "We are doubtful ………………. winning the match.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "of",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "7618086ed33f4ea0a60a9399a7356905"
        },
        {
            "question": "The thief had been hiding in the warehouse ………………… morning.",
            "description": "We use ‘since’ with the starting point. It is common after perfect tenses.",
            "answers": [
                "since",
                "from",
                "for",
                "in"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "983228d43f624a1781bebb67784992c0"
        },
        {
            "question": "Cars allow you to reach any place you want. ………………, they pose parking problems in cities.",
            "description": "We use ‘however’ to suggest that what we are going to say contradicts what we have already said. ",
            "answers": [
                "However",
                "Although",
                "Despite"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d1b7748754694694a8d0ddc0721a426c"
        },
        {
            "question": "John, as well as his cousins, …………… joining us.",
            "description": "When we connect two subjects with ‘as well as’, the verb is likely to be singular if the first verb is singular. ",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "is",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1acb5416418941a09d025d0f37a43170"
        },
        {
            "question": "You had better hire a taxi. ……………… you will arrive late.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Consequently",
                "However",
                "Otherwise"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "906ccb50c9744d97b133512010d03482"
        },
        {
            "question": "Tom ……………… ill last week.",
            "description": "The simple past is the normal tense for talking about finished actions in the past. \r\nThe present perfect cannot be used with expressions that refer to a completely finished period of time.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "57e90a6681c44c3c80b759c64817fe6c"
        },
        {
            "question": "A grandparent’s job is easier than ………………..",
            "description": "Either 'a parent's' or 'that of a parent' is possible here. ",
            "answers": [
                "a parent's",
                "that of a parent",
                "the one of a parent"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9ecda3186e9a46adb02263ec0be6ec9e"
        },
        {
            "question": "It is important ………………….",
            "description": "We put ‘not’ before infinitives and –ing forms.",
            "answers": [
                "to not worry",
                "not to worry",
                "not worry",
                "don't worry"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "5bf0b2a1c3c84cacb3f6c6e02b9ef695"
        }
    ]
}